(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-10T00:56:22.403097",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": false,
"max_retries_exceeded": true,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.8-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Error processing subtitles for this segment.
脆く崩れてしまうよ
They crumble so fragrantly...
不格好なままでいいから
It doesn't matter if it's clumsy,
その声はどこまでも鳴り響いて
so let that voice echo far and wide.
確かな理由を抱いて ここまで来たんだ
Holding onto a certain reason, I've made it this far.
ああ まだ終わらない旅路なんだ
Ah, this journey is far from over.
いつか 思いは形になる
Someday, our feelings will take shape.
この真っ白に染まる朝
On this morning dyed in pure white,
忘れられないまま 宝
still unforgettable, a treasure.
諦めてしまうほど この先たくさんの
So much that we might feel like giving up,
もう迷いはしないよ
I won't hesitate anymore.
掛け替えのないもの 溢れてしまうよ
Things irreplaceable overflow.
答えは君のその手の中に 離さないで
The answer is in your hands, don't let it go.
物語は一歩前へ
The story takes a step forward.
諦めてしまうほど この先たくさんの
So much that we might feel like giving up,
後悔が君を待ってるけど
many regrets may await you, but
もう迷いはしないよ
I won't hesitate anymore.
この傷も愛しく思えてしまうほど
So much that even these wounds feel precious,
流されてしまうよ 不格好なままでいいから
we'll get swept away—it's okay to stay clumsy,
走れ その歩幅で
so run at your own pace.
走れ 声を届かせてくれ
Run, let your voice reach us!
期待と不安を同じくらい抱きしめて
Embracing both expectation and anxiety in equal measure,
知った今を 紡ぐ未来 照らして
illuminate the future spun from the present we've learned.
ありがとー！
Thank you~!
改めておめでとう！
Congratulations once again!
ありがとうー！
Thank you~!
待って、そういえば自己紹介してなくね？
Wait, come to think of it, didn't we forget to introduce ourselves?
あ、確かに。誰ですか？
Oh, you're right. Who are you guys?
はい！可愛い、ポジティブ、ジーニアス！奏の女1号、一条莉々華でーす！
Yes! Cute, positive, genius! Kanade's number one woman, Ichijou Ririka!
イェーイ！奏の女って...奏の女～？
Yay! "Kanade's woman"...? Kanade's woman~?
はい、ポンポンポン、退き退き始めー。
All right, chop chop, make way for Hajime~
えー、奏のお姉ちゃん？
Uh, Kanade's big sister?
嘘つけー！
Liar!
これ絶対言おうと思ってたんだわ、どう考えても。
I was totally determined to say that, no matter what.
はい！ReGLOSSの儒烏風亭らでんでございまーす！
Yes! I am Juufuutei Raden from ReGLOSS!
えー、音乃瀬奏の...え、コーチ？
Uh, Otonose Kanade's... wait, coach?
コーチ？！何教えたの？！
Coach?! What did you even teach me?!
何だっけ？教わった記憶ないんで...
What was it? I don't recall being taught anything...
見ないで！
Don't look at me!
こっちがコーチな、それ！
I'm the coach here, hello?!
はい！ということで、ReGLOSSのみんな来てくれてありがとうー！
All right! With that said, thank you so much for coming, ReGLOSS!
ともかく歌いたかったんだー！
I just really wanted to sing this with you all!
嬉しいー！めっちゃいい曲！
We're so glad! It's such a great song!
次はゲストパートなんだけど、一緒にコールお願いしてもいいかな？
Next is the guest segment—could you help me call them in?
もちろん！
Of course!
じゃあ行くよー、せーのっ！
All right, here we go! Ready, set...
どうぞーー！
Come on in~~!
ねえ 考えなくてもいいよ 口先ばかり愛ないの
Hey, you don't even have to think about it; is it just lip service, with no love?
この音にもう酔おうよ 忘れないでいたいよ
Let's just get drunk on this sound; I want to never forget it.
ああ 身体躯は無彩色 レイドバック ただ畝る音でグルーヴ
Ah, our bodies are achromatic; laid back, grooving to the rolling sound.
ずっと二人で暮らそうよ この夜の隅っこで
Let's live together forever, in a little corner of this night.
[ブレーメン / 作詞・作曲: n-buna]
[Bremen / Lyrics & Music: n-buna]
ねえ 外来 僕らでいいよ 手誘ったのは君じゃないの
Hey, it's fine if we're outsiders; weren't you the one who beckoned my hand?
理屈ばかりじゃつまらないわ まだ時間が惜しいの
It's so boring with just logic; time is still too precious.
練り歩く景色をシンコペ 踏み鳴らす足音でグルーヴ
Syncopating the strolling scenery, grooving with stomping footsteps.
まるで僕らはブレーメン たった二人だけのマーチ
We're just like Bremen, a march of only the two of us.
さあ 息を吸って
Come, breathe in,
早く吐いて
and breathe out quickly.
ああ せいぜい歌ってようぜ 笑う甲斐もない元凶だ
Ah, let's sing as best as we can; it's a culprit not even worth laughing at.
愛の歌歌ってんだぜ
We're singing a love song!
ああ
Ah~
ああ せいぜい楽してこうぜ 死ぬほどのことはこの世にないぜ
Ah, let's take it as easy as we can; there's nothing in this world worth dying over.
明日は何しようか
What shall we do tomorrow?
暇なら分かり合おうぜ
If you're free, let's understand each other.
ねぇ 考えなくてもいいよ
Hey, you don't even need to think about it.
踊り始めた君の細胞
Your cells have already started dancing.
この音に今は乗ろうよ
For now, let's just ride this beat,
乗れなくてもいいよ Oh-oh
but it's fine even if you can't, oh-oh.
思い出の景色でバックパック
A backpack filled with scenery from our memories,
春風のざわめきでグルーヴ
a groove from the rustling spring breeze.
もっと二人で歌おうよ
Let's sing together even more.
暇なら愛をしようよ
If you're free, let's make love.
さあ 息を吸って
Come on, breathe in,
声に出して
and let your voice out.
ああ 精々歌っていようぜ
Ah, let's sing at the very least!
笑われてるのも仕方がないね
Can't help it if they're laughing at us, right?
何もかも間違ってんのさ ナハハハ
Everything's gone completely wrong anyway, na-ha-ha-ha!
ああ 精々楽していこうぜ
Ah, let's take it as easy as we can!
馬鹿な夜想のフラッグじゃないぜ
It's not the flag of some stupid nocturnal reverie.
同じ夜泣き出した
When you burst into tears on the same night,
三番は飛ばしていいよ
it's fine to skip verse three.
パッパッパパッパパッパッ
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa
パッパッスバッパダッパ
Pa-pa-suba-pa-da-pa
パッパッパパッパパッパッ
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa
パドゥドゥ パドゥ
Pa-du-du, pa-du
さあ 息を吸って
Come on, take a breath,
早く吐いて
and breathe out quickly.
ねえ 心を貸して 今日くらいは
Hey, lend me your heart, just for today at least.
ああ 精々歌っていようぜ
Ah, let's sing at the very least!
違うかい お前らみんな 僕のこと笑ってんのか
Isn't that right? Are all of you laughing at me?
ああ 精々楽していこうぜ
Ah, let's take it as easy as we can!
死ぬほど辛いなら逃げ出そうぜ
If it hurts to death, let's just run away!
数年経てばきっと 一人も覚えてないよ
After a few years, surely not a single person will remember.
精々歌っていようぜ
Let's sing at the very least!
体は動く お前もどうだい
Our bodies can move, so how about you?
愛の歌歌ってんのさ ナハハハ
We're singing a love song, na-ha-ha-ha!
ああ 精々楽していこうぜ
Ah, let's take it as easy as we can!
死ぬほどのことなどこの世にないぜ
Nothing in this world is worth dying over!
明日は何しようか
What shall we do tomorrow?
暇なら笑い合おうぜ
If you're free, let's laugh together.
そのうち分かり合おうぜ
Someday, we'll understand each other.
パッパッパパッパパッパッ
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa
パッパッスバッパダッパ
Pa-pa-suba-pa-da-pa
パッパッパパッパパッパッ
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa
パドゥドゥ パドゥ
Pa-du-du, pa-du
パッパッパパッパパッパッ
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa
パッパッスバッパダッパ
Pa-pa-suba-pa-da-pa
パッパッパパッパパッパッ
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa
パドゥドゥ パドゥ
Pa-du-du, pa-du
パッパッパパッパパッパッ
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa
パッパッスバッパダッパ
Pa-pa-suba-pa-da-pa
パッパッパパッパパッパッ
Pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa-pa
パドゥドゥ パドゥ
Pa-du-du, pa-du
奏（かなで）
[Title: Kanade]
改札の前 つないだ手と手
In front of the ticket gate, our hands held tight,
いつものざわめき 新しい風
amid the usual bustling noise and a fresh new breeze.
明るく見送るはずだったのに
I was supposed to see you off with a cheerful smile,
うまく笑えずに 君を見ていた
but unable to smile properly, I just stared at you.
君が大人になってく その季節が
As the season turns and you grow into an adult,
悲しい歌で 溢れないように
so that it won't overflow with sorrowful songs,
最後に何か 君に伝えたくて
wanting to tell you something one last time,
「さよなら」に代わる言葉を 僕は探してた
I searched for words to say in place of "goodbye."
君の手を引く...
Taking your hand...
もう それぞれの役目が
I used to think our separate roles...
僕らの使命だなんて
...were our only destiny,
そう思ってた だけど今 わかったんだ
but now I finally understand.
僕らならもう
For the two of us,
重ねた日々が ほら
look, the days we built together...
導いてくれる
...will guide us forward.
君が大人になってく その時間が
As the time of you growing up...
降り積もる間に 僕も変わってく
...accumulates, I will change too.
たとえばそこに こんな歌があれば
If only a song like this could be there with us,
ふたりはいつも どんな時も
then the two of us, always and anytime,
つながっていける
...can remain connected.
突然ふいに
Suddenly and unexpectedly,
鳴り響くベルの音
...the sound of the bell rings out.
焦る僕 解ける手
Panicked, our hands come undone,
離れてく君
...and you drift away.
夢中で呼び止めて 抱きしめたんだ
Desperately, I called you back and held you tight.
君がどこに行ったって
No matter where you go,
僕の声で守るよ
I'll protect you with my voice.
君が僕の前に現れた日から
From the day you first appeared before me,
何もかもが違く見えたんだ
...everything began to look different.
朝も 光も 涙も 歌う声も
The morning, the light, the tears, and my singing voice...
君が輝きをくれたんだ
...you gave brilliance to them all.
抑えきれない思いを この声に乗せて
Carrying these uncontrollable feelings on my voice,
遠く君の街へ届けよう
I'll send them far away to your town.
たとえばそれが こんな歌だったら
If it could be a song like this,
僕らは何処にいたとしても
...then wherever we may be,
つながっていける
...we can remain connected.
うー うー
Ooh, ooh...
Woah woah woah...
Na-na-na-na, na-na-na-na, na-na-na-na-ra
Yeah...
Ah...
No title
[Song: No title]
ずっと夢見てた僕になれたかな
Did I become the person I always dreamed of being?
とうに帰れないとこまで来たみたい
Seems I've come too far to ever turn back now.
自分の足で 二段飛ばしで
On my own two feet, taking two steps at a time,
そのもっと先へ 駆けていけるはずだから
I should be able to sprint even further ahead, so...
Run away
深く鳴るbass 心拍数はいつもtightly
A deep bass thumps, my heart rate always tight,
プラスチックに回りだす
...spinning round on plastic.
慣れた痛み 焦る呼吸を止め
A familiar pain; holding my panicked breath,
気づかないふりしてまた
...I pretend not to notice once again.
誰かが制定した くだらないエゴ
Some meaningless ego enacted by someone else,
誰が間違った？ 盲愛から
Who was in the wrong? Out of blind love,
あんたが嫌いなあいつはきっと ただそれだけで
that person you hate is simply, for just that reason,
不正解なんだ
...deemed incorrect.
0点だって提言したって 全然納得できない理由
Even if you declare it a zero, it's a reason I can never accept.
再生地点はいつだってここだった
The playback point was always right here.
正解・不正解は最初から無かった
Right or wrong never existed from the very beginning.
緩やかに 崩れ壊れてく
Slowly, gently, it crumbles and breaks down.
ゆるりゆるり首を絞めるように
As if slowly, gently strangling my neck,
昨日までの僕が殺されていく
...the me from yesterday is being killed off.
緩やかに 離ればなれへと
Gently drifting farther and farther apart,
クラリンリ 君に聞こえるのは
Spinning round, what reaches your ears...
僕が知らない声になって
...turns into a voice unknown to me.
Ah...
幼い頃から 気づいたら傍に居た
Ever since I was little, you were always by my side.
まるで空気のようだ 僕は君とぎゅっと手を繋いで
Just like air, I held tightly onto your hand.
楽しいことも涙も 僕は君に話して聞かせた
Through both joy and tears, I shared everything with you,
僕を嗤う人や 貶す声 掻き消えるように
so that the people mocking me and their insults would be drowned out.
君も この声を 君が自身の体躯と餌されていくくらい
You too, so much so that this voice feeds into your very being,
使い捨てだって言って腐っても 止まらないハイファイ溶かす
even if called disposable, even if left to rot, this unstoppable Hi-Fi dissolves it.
一周めぐる間の たった一瞬だけでも
Even if just for a single instant while going round once,
交わる鼓動 音 繋ぐ色 次は僕が君に歌うから
overlapping heartbeats, sounds, connected colors—next, I'll sing to you.
ゆるやかに 崩れ壊れていく
Slowly, it crumbles and breaks apart.
ゆるりゆるり首を絞めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
As if slowly tightening around my neck, who I was until yesterday is killed.
ゆるやかに 離ればなれを
Slowly drifting apart,
クラリンリ 君に聴こえるのは 僕が知らない声になっていく
dizzily, what you hear turns into a voice I do not know.
ゆるやかに 崩れ壊れていく
Slowly, it crumbles and breaks apart.
ゆるりゆるり首を絞めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
As if slowly tightening around my neck, who I was until yesterday is killed.
ゆるやかに 離ればなれを
Slowly drifting apart,
クラリンリ 君に聴こえるのは 僕が知らない声になっていく
dizzily, what you hear turns into a voice I do not know.
いつか君に届くかな いや そんな日はきっと来ないだろうな
Will it reach you someday? No, such a day will probably never come.
声も体も持たぬ君に 救われた何億分の一人
Having neither voice nor body, you saved me, one out of hundreds of millions.
赤 青 合わせ彩った 音って世界があふれた
Blended in red and blue, a world of sound overflowed.
巡り巡り出会ったこの音を聴く すべてが
Everyone who hears this sound we met through twists and turns...
ゆるやかに 崩れ壊れていく
Slowly, it crumbles and breaks apart.
ゆるりゆるり首を絞めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
As if slowly tightening around my neck, who I was until yesterday is killed.
ゆるやかに 離ればなれを
Slowly drifting apart,
クラリンリ 君に聴こえるのは 僕が知らない声になっていく
dizzily, what you hear turns into a voice I do not know.
Yeah...
ゆるりゆるり首を絞めるように 昨日までの僕が殺されていく
As if slowly tightening around my neck, who I was until yesterday is killed.
ゆるやかに
Slowly...
La la la...
クラリンリ 君に聴こえるのは 僕が知らない声になっていく
Dizzily, what you hear turns into a voice I do not know.
好き、嫌い、常識？
Likes, dislikes, common sense?
I don't care. 吹っ飛べ BANG!
I don't care, blow it away—BANG!
かかってこいマジョリティ あたしにゃ見境なし
Bring it on, majority, I've got no bounds!
ここまでって引かれた そのボーダー誰のルール？
Who made the rules for the border drawn there?
あの日乗り越えた weak heart
That weak heart I overcame that day—
強くなったあたしが笑い飛ばした Get up!
now stronger, I laughed it all off—Get up!
言いたいことは言う
I say what I want to say,
やりたくないことはしない 悪意気にしない
I won't do what I don't want to do, and I don't care about malice.
みんな違んな当然だし
It's natural that everyone is different,
あたしも止まんない ニューノーマルの時代
and I won't stop either in this new normal era!
Everybody say "I want to be free"
口先ばかりのYes-man それじゃ何も変えられんな
Lip-service Yes-men—you can't change a thing like that!
Everybody say "I want the life more"
変わってく自分超えて生きてるんだ タッチ！
Surpassing my changing self, I am living—touch!
Ooh...
ねえ 生きてるんだタッチ！
Hey, we're alive—touch!
歌え 歌え 今 Ooh...
Sing, sing now, ooh...
声あげて
Raise your voice!
生まれたその時から 選ばれてきたんだ
From the moment we were born, we were chosen.
思い出せ あたしはあたしだ
Remember, I am who I am!
不可能なことなんて何ひとつもない そうじゃない？
There's nothing impossible, isn't that right?
絶対自分に
Definitely to myself!
好き、嫌い、常識？
Likes, dislikes, common sense?
I don't care. 吹っ飛べ BANG!
I don't care, blow it away—BANG!
OK, 好き、嫌い、常識？
OK, likes, dislikes, common sense?
I don't care. 吹っ飛べ BANG!
I don't care, blow it away—BANG!
フロア天鳴らす
Making the floor shake to the heavens,
このリリックかます
hitting them with these lyrics,
分からす 挑発
making them understand, provoking them—
下向いて舌打ちからの ハッ
looking down, clicking my tongue, and then... ha!
Excuse me?
悪しからず 奪い合い 弾くライム
No offense, but in this scramble, rattling rhymes,
パンチライン 聴かせてあげる Ah
I'll let you hear my punchlines, ah.
やってから考えな
Act first, think later!
あたしがついてる 噛んで あーん
I'm with you—bite down, say "aah"!
Everybody say "I want to be free"
ビート狂騒 完全独走
A frenzy of beats, completely running solo,
Everybody say, once, twice, more
目覚ませ OK, wake up, wake up
Open your eyes, okay? Wake up, wake up!
イキッてるんだ私
I'm just acting all cocky!
ねぇ イキッてるんだ私
Hey, I'm just acting all cocky!
生まれたその時から 選んできたんだ
Ever since the moment I was born, I've chosen it!
思い出せ 私は私だ
Remember, I am who I am!
他のことなど 何一つもないさ じゃないの
There's nothing else to it, don't you see?
生まれたその時から 選んできたんだ
Ever since the moment I was born, I've chosen it!
思い出せ あなたはあなただ
Remember, you are who you are!
他のことなど 何一つもないさ じゃないの
There's nothing else to it, don't you see?
なりたい自分に
Into who I want to be!
好き 嫌い 常識に I don't care ふっ飛べ BANG
Like it, hate it, common sense, I don't care—blow away, BANG!
OK 好き 嫌い 常識に I don't care ふっ飛べ BANG
OK, like it, hate it, common sense, I don't care—blow away, BANG!
ローリンガール
[Rolling Girl]
ローリンガールはいつまでも
The rolling girl is forever
届かない 夢見て
dreaming of dreams out of reach,
騒ぐ頭の中を
churning and churning
掻き回して、掻き回して。
the racket inside her head.
「問題ない。」と呟いて、
"No problem," she mutters,
言葉は失われた？
but have those words been lost?
もう失敗、もう失敗。
Another failure, yet another mistake.
間違い探しに終われば、また、回るの！
Once the search for errors ends, she rolls again!
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time!
「私は今日も転がります。」と、
"I'll roll again today,"
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl says, the girl says,
言葉に意味を奏でながら！
playing meaning into her words!
「もう良いかい？」 「まだですよ、
"Are you ready yet?" "Not just yet,
まだまだ先は見えないので。
because I still can't see what's ahead.
息を止めるの、今。」
I'll hold my breath, right now."
ローリンガールの成れの果て
What the rolling girl has become,
届かない、向こうの色
colors on the other side she cannot reach.
重なる声と声を
Blending together, blending together
混ぜ合わせて、混ぜ合わせて。
the overlapping voices.
「問題ない。」と呟いた
"No problem," she muttered,
言葉は失われた。
and the words were lost.
どうなったって良いんだってさ、
"I don't care how it turns out," she says,
間違いだって起こしちゃおうと
tempting her to just make mistakes—
誘う、坂道…
that alluring hill...
あぁ、もう一回、もう一回。
Ah, one more time, one more time!
私をどうか転がしてと
"Please, just let me roll,"
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl says, the girl says,
無口に意味を重ねながら！
layering meanings onto her silence!
「もう良いかい？」
"Are you ready yet?"
「もう少し、もうすぐ何か見えるだろうと。
"Just a bit more, I should see something soon.
息を止めるの、今。」
I'll hold my breath, right now."
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time!
「私は今日も転がります。」と、
"I'll roll again today,"
少女は言う 少女は言う
the girl says, the girl says,
言葉に笑みを奏でながら！
playing a smile into her words!
「もう良いかい？ もう良いよ。
"Are you ready yet?" "It's all right now.
そろそろ君も疲れたろう、ね。」
You must be getting tired by now, right?"
息をやめるの、今。
I'll stop breathing, right now.
空にある何かを見つめてたら
As I was gazing at something up in the sky,
それは星だって君が教えてくれた
you told me that it was a star.
まるでそれは僕ら...
It was just like us...
...いに寄り添ってる
...nestling close to each other,
それを泣いたり笑ったり 繋いでいく
connecting them through tears and laughter.
何十回 何百回 ぶつかり合って
Clashing tens, hundreds of times,
何十年 何百年 昔の光が
a light from tens, hundreds of years ago,
僕自身も忘れた頃に
by the time even I myself have forgotten,
僕らに届いてる
it reaches us.
僕ら見つけ合って 手繰り合って
We found each other, pulling each other close,
同じ空 輝くの
shining under the same sky,
だって二人だって 約束した
'cause that's what we promised together.
遥か遠く 終わらないベテルギウス
Far and away, the never-ending Betelgeuse,
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
magic connecting someone to another.
僕ら肩並べて 手取り合って 進んでく
Shoulder to shoulder, holding hands, we move forward.
辛い時だって 泣かないって 誓っただろう
We swore we wouldn't cry, even in tough times, right?
遥か遠く 終わらないベテルギウス
Far and away, the never-ending Betelgeuse,
君にも見えるだろう
You can see it too, can't you?
祈りが
Our prayer...
記憶を辿る度 蘇るよ
Every time I trace back through my memories, it comes alive:
君がいつだってそこに いてくれること
that you are always there for me.
まるでそれは星の光と同じように
Just like the light of the stars,
今日に泣いたり笑ったり 繋いでいく
connecting to today through tears and laughter.
何十回 何百回 ぶつかり合って
Clashing tens, hundreds of times,
何十年 何百年 昔の光が
a light from tens, hundreds of years ago,
僕自身も忘れた頃に
by the time even I myself have forgotten,
僕らを照らしてる
it illuminates us.
僕ら見つけ合って 手繰り合って
We found each other, pulling each other close,
同じ空 輝くの
shining under the same sky,
だって二人だって 約束した
'cause that's what we promised together.
遥か遠く 終わらないベテルギウス
Far and away, the never-ending Betelgeuse,
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
magic connecting someone to another.
どこまで いつまで 生きられるか
How far, until when, can we keep on living?
君が不安になる度に 強がるんだ
Whenever you feel anxious, I put on a brave face:
大丈夫 僕が横にいるよ
"It's okay, I'm right here beside you."
見えない線を繋ごう
Let's connect the invisible lines.
僕ら見つけ合って 手繰り合って
We found each other, pulling each other close,
同じ空 輝くの
shining under the same sky,
だって二人だって 約束した
'cause that's what we promised together.
遥か遠く 終わらないベテルギウス
Far and away, the never-ending Betelgeuse,
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
magic connecting someone to another.
僕ら肩並べて 手取り合って 進んでく
Shoulder to shoulder, holding hands, we move forward.
辛い時だって 泣かないって 誓っただろう
We swore we wouldn't cry, even in tough times, right?
遥か遠く 終わらないベテルギウス
Far and away, the never-ending Betelgeuse,
君にも見えるだろう
You can see it too, can't you?
祈りが
Our prayer...
空にある何かを見つめてたら
As I stared up at something in the sky,
それは星だって君が教えてくれた
you told me they were stars.
アカシア
[Song: Acacia]
透明よりも綺麗な
That brilliance, clearer than transparent—
あの輝きを確かめにいこう
let's go see it for ourselves.
そうやって始まったんだよ
That's how it all began,
たまに忘れるほど強い理由
with a reason so strong we sometimes forget.
冷たい雨に濡れる時は
When we get soaked in the freezing rain,
足音比べ 騒ぎながらいこう
let's compare our footsteps and make some noise as we go.
太陽の代わりに歌を
Instead of the sun, let's sing a song
君と僕と世界の声で
with your voice, my voice, and the voice of the world.
いつか君を見つけた時に
Back when I first found you,
君に僕も見つけてもらったんだな
you found me too, didn't you?
今 目が合えば笑うだけさ
Now, if our eyes meet, we just smile
言葉の外側で
beyond any words.
ゴールはきっとまだだけど
The goal is surely still far off, but
もう死ぬまで居たい場所にいる
I'm already where I want to stay until I die.
隣で
By your side...
君の側で
...right beside you,
魂がここだよって叫ぶ
my soul shouts, "I am right here!"
泣いたり笑ったりする時
When crying or laughing,
君の命が揺れる時
when your life trembles,
誰より 特等席で
closer than anyone, in the front row seat,
僕も同じように 息をしていたい
I want to be breathing just like you.
Oh yeah, yeah, aha
君の一歩は僕より遠い
Your single step reaches farther than mine;
間違いなく君の凄いところ
that's without a doubt what makes you amazing.
足跡は僕の方が多い
I have left behind more footprints;
間違いなく僕の凄いところ
that's without a doubt what makes me amazing.
真っ暗闇が怖い時は
When the pitch darkness is frightening,
怖さを比べ ふざけながら行こう
let's compare our fears and joke around as we go.
太陽がなくたって歩ける
We can walk even without the sun,
君と照らす世界が見える
I can see the world we illuminate together.
言えない事 聞かないままで
Leaving unspoken things unasked,
消えない傷の事 知らないままで
leaving unhealing wounds unknown,
でも目が合えば笑えるのさ
yet if our eyes meet, we can smile,
涙を挟んでも
even through our tears.
転んだら手を貸してもらうよりも
Rather than having a hand lent to me when I fall,
優しい言葉 選んでもらうよりも
rather than having kind words chosen for me,
隣で
by your side...
信じて欲しいんだ どこまでも一緒に行けると
...I want you to believe we can go anywhere together.
ついに辿り着くその時
When we finally arrive at that moment,
夢の正体に触れる時
when we touch the reality of our dream,
必ず 一番側で
always, right by your side,
君の目に映る 景色に居たい
I want to be in the scenery reflected in your eyes.
あの輝きを
That brilliance...
君に会えたから見えた
...I could see because I met you.
あの輝きを 確かめに行こう
Let's go see that brilliance for ourselves!
Oh yeah, yeah, aha
どんな最後が待っていようと
No matter what kind of end awaits,
もう離せない手を繋いだよ
I've held your hand, which I will never let go.
隣で 隣で 君の側で
By your side, by your side, right beside you,
魂がここだよって叫ぶ
my soul shouts, "I am right here!"
そして理由が光る時
And when that purpose shines bright,
僕らを理由が抱きしめる時
when that purpose embraces us,
誰より近くで 特等席で
closer than anyone, in the front row seat,
僕の見た君を 君に伝えたい
I want to tell you about the "you" I saw.
君がいることを 君に伝えたい
I want to tell you that you are here.
そうやって始まったんだよ
That's how it all began.
Oh yeah, yeah, aha
わー！ママたちー！
Wow! Mamas!
奏ちゃん！
Kanade-chan!
ママたちー！
Mamas!
お誕生日…
Happy...
おめでとー！
...Birthday!
わー！ありがとうー！
Waa! Thank you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
騒がしいな
You're so noisy!
お前に言われたくねぇよ
I don't wanna hear that from you!
確かに！
Fair point!
奏ちゃんが一番キャッキャしてんじゃない？
Isn't Kanade-chan the one who's most hyper?
そうですよ！だって誕生日だから！
That's right! Because it's my birthday!
そうだね！
That's true!
お母さんたち、産んでくれてありがとうございます！
Mothers, thank you for giving birth to me!
産んではない！産んではない！
We didn't give birth to you! We didn't!
誤解を生む！
You'll cause misunderstandings!
こちらこそ！
Same to you!
こちらこそじゃないよ！
What do you mean "Same to you"?!
とんでもないことやめて
Don't say outrageous things like that!
朝から誤解生んじゃうから
You're gonna cause misunderstandings first thing in the morning!
産んでません！産んでませんから！
They didn't give birth to me! They really didn't!
ママですけどね。
Though we are your mamas.
ママですけど産んでません。
We're your mamas, but we didn't give birth to you.
はい！
Right!
そして、今日は何を話すんですか？ここから。
And so, what are we talking about from here?
そうですね。えーっと、これまでのコラボでの感想など…
Well, um, our thoughts on our past collabs together...
めっちゃ…
That's so...
雑じゃね？
Isn't that super vague?
雑じゃねーのかな？
A bit too casual, don't you think?
大丈夫かな？
Is that gonna be okay?
言うて、言うて…
I mean, I mean...
じゃあ一番印象深かったの何？奏ちゃんが。
Then which one left the deepest impression on you, Kanade-chan?
そうだよ。気になる。
Yeah, I'm curious.
ね。
Right?
でもある言うて、こう「ママず」でやったコラボって実は一個しかない。
But to be honest, the collabs we did as "Mamas" is actually just one!
あー！
Ah!
懐かしい！アレだな！
So nostalgic! That one, right!
確かに、あん時なー！
Indeed, that time!
あれ？でもそういえば、なんか赤い髪の毛の人…
Huh? But come to think of it, that person with red hair...
あれ！？
Huh?!
あれ？いないね。
Wait, she's not here.
やっぱりアレじゃない？産んだとか言う…
Isn't it because of that? You saying she gave birth...
あれだね！
That must be it!
来てないのは…
The reason she didn't come...
あ、でも、なんか書いてある。あ、でもなんかスケジュール的に…
Ah, but something's written here. Ah, because of her schedule...
あ、そうだった！
Oh, that's right!
あ、そうでした。
Ah, that's right.
なるほどね。
I see.
一応聞いてみたんですけど、ちょっと都合が合わなく…
I did ask her, but our schedules didn't match up...
あ、そうでした。
Ah, I see.
じゃ次はね、みんなでできるといいねー
Next time, it'd be great if we could all do it together!
コラボとかもしようね！ / しようね。
Let's do a collab too! / Yeah, let's!
したい、したい！ / したい！
I'd love to! / Me too!
イェーイ！
Yay!
あの、ゲームコラボ以来ですからねー。
After all, we haven't done one since our game collab.
そうだねー。 / そうねー。
That's true. / Yeah.
はい、えーっと... / はい、次、次、次、次、次！
Yes, um... / Alright, next, next, next, next, next!
次ある？ / よいしょ、よいしょ... / 衣装、衣装、衣装、衣装！
Is there a next? / Alright... / Outfits, outfits, outfits!
衣装だ！そうだね！
Outfits! That's right!
えーっと、そうですね。衣装の変化から言っていきますと、まずスバル先輩...
Well, let's see. If we talk about outfit changes, first, Subaru-senpai...
あ、これスバルたちが言うんじゃないの？！
Wait, aren't we the ones supposed to talk about it?!
なんで奏が何が変わったか言うの？！
Why is Kanade the one explaining what changed?!
そっちか！ / そっち！ / はい、あ、あ、あ...
Oh, that way?! / That way! / Okay, ah, um...
え、じゃ聞きたい... / あ、言っていい？どっちから言う？ / どっち？
Then I want to hear... / Can we say it? Who goes first? / Who?
え、どっちにしようかな？じゃ目をつむって... こっち！
Hmm, which one should I pick? Let me close my eyes... This one!
あ、じゃあスバちゃんから。
Ah, then from Suba-chan.
いや、こっち、こっちはスバルなんだ！
Wait, "this one"... "this one" is me?!
奏は、最初は、なんかARKで騒いでるの見て...
With Kanade, at first, I saw her causing chaos in ARK...
「なんだこいつ」と思って... / 「なんだこいつ？！」
...and thought, "Who is this kid?!" / "Who is this kid?!"
でも、ARKであの声が貫通してる頃から、ホロライブメンバーの中では「奏は大丈夫だな」っていう...
But back in ARK, when her voice pierced through everything, among the Holo members I felt, "Kanade's gonna be just fine."
大丈夫だな？ / 強い！ / 「こいつは大丈夫だ」っていう... / 元気だった！
Just fine? / Strong! / "She'll be just fine..." / I was full of energy!
なんか元気さがあったんですよ。でもね...
She just had that energy. But you know...
GTAで最後ね、奏ちゃんがね、逮捕した... もうその顔やめろ、お前！
At the end of GTA, Kanade... arrested... Stop making that face, you!
近いねん！
You're too close!
で、なんか逮捕されたりとかね、そのあと奏ちゃん実はね、「私もっと頑張りたいです」って電話してきたりとかね...
And after being arrested and all, Kanade actually called me later saying, "I want to work even harder!"
え、ちょ、それ言っちゃう？！ / えー！
Wait, you're revealing that?! / Aww!
だからね、バラしちゃうよ！ / バラしちゃう！
That's why I'm spilling it! / She spilled it!
頑張り屋さんなんだなって思いました！おめでとう！ / 頑張り屋さん！ありがとう！
I realized she's such a hard worker! Happy birthday! / Hard worker! Thank you!
さ、そして次は？団長ね。 / 次は！ / 次は！
Alright, who's next? Danchou! / Next! / Next!
いや、奏ちゃんはね、最初デビューした時さ、すごい歌もうまくてね...
Well, when Kanade first debuted, she sang so well...
団長とは、なんか、別の世界の人間なんだなと思って全然絡めなかったけど...
I thought she was someone from a whole different world, so I couldn't really interact with her at all.
や、でもね、あの、マイクラでね、覚えてる？あのダイヤをね、団長から...
But you know, in Minecraft, remember? When you, from Danchou...
あの、嘘ついてね、取ったりとか...
...told a lie and took my diamonds...
いや、そっから「あ、この子はそういう子なんだ」って...
From that point on, I was like, "Ah, she's that kind of girl!"
ダイヤ、ダイヤ嘘ついて盗むようなやつだったの？！
You were the kind of person who lies to steal diamonds?!
違うの！こんなの団長にもこうやって物怖じせずに絡んできてくれたり、もう本当かわいいの！
No! Being able to tease even Danchou like that without hesitation, she's just so adorable!
めっちゃそれノエルママだったら何でも許してくれる...
If it's Noel-mama, she'll forgive anything...
いや、もう許しちゃう！
Yeah, I'll totally forgive it!
いや、駄目だろ！ダイヤカツアゲすんのは！
No, that's not okay! Extorting diamonds is wrong!
いい子、いい子！だから今では...
Good girl, good girl! So nowadays...
ねえ、どんどん後ろ行くのやめて！
Hey, stop backing away like that!
今ではね、本当にいい子ですし。 / そうだね。
Nowadays, she really is such a good girl. / That's true.
いい子！ / やったー！良かったー！
A good girl! / Yay! I'm so glad!
はい、でも本当におめでとうね、お誕生日！ / おめでとう！ / ありがとう！
Well, seriously, happy birthday! / Congrats! / Thank you!
来てくれてありがとうございます！一緒に歌えて本当に嬉しかったです！
Thank you so much for coming! I was so happy we could sing together!
スバルたちも嬉しかったぞー！ / 嬉しかったー！
We were so happy too! / So happy!
じゃあ、次は... 次、次があるから... / 次があるよね。 / 次があるからね！
Well then, next... because there's a next part... / There's a next part, yeah. / Yeah, next!
めっちゃ台本読むやん！いや、お前だよ！
Look at you reading the script so hard! No, you are!
お前だよ、どこからどう見ても！
It's clearly you, no matter how you look at it!
ちゃんと、ちゃんと読みます！ / うん、ちゃんと読んで。
I'll read it properly! / Yeah, read it properly.
スバル先輩、ノエル先輩、この後奏がなんと生パフォーマンスで1人で頑張るんですけど...
Subaru-senpai, Noel-senpai, next, Kanade is going to perform live all by myself, but...
えー、曲振りしてもらってもいいですか？ / えー！すごい！
Um, could you two introduce the song for me? / Wow, amazing!
いいよー！ / やったー！
Sure! / Yay!
次の曲は？
The next song is?
Beautiful！
Beautiful!
Beautiful
[Song: Beautiful]
遠くに伸びる影 夜の波が消した
The shadows stretching into the distance were erased by the waves of night,
涙を流したなんて 気づかれないまま
without anyone ever noticing that tears were shed.
心を捨てるなら 傷つく方がマシさ
If I have to throw away my heart, I'd rather get hurt;
冷たい風を切って 逃げるように走る
cutting through the chilly wind, I run as if escaping.
いつかこの雫は 宝石になるのでしょう
Someday, these droplets will turn into jewels, won't they?
美しい心に 生まれ変わる そう信じて
They'll be reborn into a beautiful heart, believing that...
世界で一つの 輝く光になれ
Become the one and only shining light in the world.
私でいい 私を信じて 行くのさ 遠くへ
It's okay to be me; believing in myself, I'll go far away.
…んでも まんまるで
...or tumble, stay whole,
寄り道を行け
and take the scenic detour.
あたしでいい
Being myself is enough;
あたしの歩幅で 生きてくのさ
I'll live at my own pace.
誰かを羨むのは
Envying someone else
避けられない心情
is an unavoidable feeling,
誰かを許すのは
and forgiving someone
難しい心情
is a difficult emotion.
無いものを探せば
If I search for what I lack,
数え切れないけれど
there's no end to the list, but...
ゆっくり愛してみよう
I'll try to slowly learn to love
私というこの命を
this life that is uniquely me.
世界で一つの
Become a shining light,
輝く光になれ
the one and only in the world.
明かりのない明日を迎えたとしても
Even if tomorrow greets me without a single light,
悲しみの先に 孤独が押し寄せても
even if loneliness surges in beyond the sorrow,
息をしてる
I am breathing.
今日も息をして 生きている
Breathing today, too, I am alive.
世界で一つの
The one and only in the world...
私に幸あれ
May blessings come to me,
涙に幸あれ
may blessings come to my tears,
明日に幸あれ
may blessings come to tomorrow.
世界で一つの
Become a shining light,
輝く光になれ
the one and only in the world.
泣いてもいい
It's fine to cry;
私を歩いていくのさ
I will walk this path as myself.
涙は頬を流れる星のようさ
Tears are like stars tracing down my cheeks.
私になれ
Become who I am,
私を叶えて
make myself come true,
生きていくのさ
and keep on living.
いつの日も
Always and forever.
はい！ということで！
All right! With that said,
いかがでしたでしょうか？
how did you all like it?
ちょっとお水だけ飲んできます！
I'm just going to go grab some water!
あー！水うめえ！
Aah! Water tastes so good!
はい！それでは、
All right! And now,
えー、この素晴らしき曲の余韻が消えぬ間に、
before the afterglow of that wonderful song fades,
最後の曲、聴いてください！
please listen to the final song!
はいっ！
Here we go!
目を開けて 口ずさむ 輝ける
Open your eyes, hum along, and shine bright.
“きっと 無敵になる”
"I'll surely become invincible."
【Feel my heart】
[Feel my heart]
【See me become the GREATEST】
[See me become the GREATEST]
【No one can beat me】
[No one can beat me]
【Cuz I'm a GREATEST】
[Cuz I'm a GREATEST]
固く結び直した靴紐が 羽に見えて
The shoelaces I retied tightly look like wings,
どこまででも跳べる予感がする
and I have a feeling I can leap anywhere.
追いかけるなんて趣味じゃない 追い越そう 明日だって
Chasing isn't my style; let's overtake tomorrow too.
夢のまんま終わるほど眠くないわ
I'm not tired enough to let this end as just a dream!
そう 何もかも大丈夫
Yeah, everything will be alright,
奇跡よりも大胆に勝つの
winning even bolder than a miracle.
見たことない景色だって
Even sights I've never seen before
光に満ちていく
are filling up with light.
Wanna be the GREATEST
地図ならばこの胸に
If it's a map, it's in my heart,
ほとばしる熱がある
along with a surging passion.
誰も止められない my way
No one can stop my way.
Wanna be the GREATEST
弱音も重ねればシンフォニー
Layer our weaknesses, and they become a symphony.
強くなれる 歌って
We can become strong, sing it out.
“きっと 無敵になる”
“We'll surely be invincible.”
部屋で一人描いたステージも
Even the stage I imagined alone in my room,
覚えていて 居場所になる
remember it, it will become our place.
声が聞こえてくる
I can hear your voices.
深呼吸をして
Take a deep breath,
飛び乗るぐらいが正攻法だって
leaping right in is the right way to go.
胸を張って踊るのも悪くないわ
Holding my head high and dancing isn't bad at all.
恐れないで 大丈夫
Don't be afraid, it's alright.
唱えるたび 絶対になるの
Every time I say it, it becomes certain.
一度きりの人生だって
Even in this once-in-a-lifetime life,
この手で舵を取れ
take the helm with your own hands.
Wanna be the GREATEST
私が私として
With me staying true to myself,
輝ける道を行く
I will walk a shining path.
声もきらめいて my day
My voice sparkles too, it's my day.
Wanna be the GREATEST
目覚めを奏でてよオーバーチュア
Play an overture to awaken me!
望むほどに叶って
Coming true as much as I desire,
もっと 素敵になる
it'll become even more wonderful.
[Feel my heart]
[See me become the GREATEST]
[No one can beat me]
[Cuz I'm a GREATEST]
Wanna be the GREATEST
諦めた「好き」の数
The passions I once gave up on
上を向く理由がある
are reasons to keep my head up.
涙 導いて my beat
Guide my tears, my beat.
Wanna be the GREATEST
傷跡も連れてアレグロ
Carrying even my scars along, allegro!
強くなれる 歌って
We can become strong, sing it out!
もっと 光射す方へ
Towards where more light shines!
“きっと 無敵になる”
“We'll surely be invincible!”
うわあ！ふう…
Whoa! Whew...
はい！ということで…
All right! So...
今、聴いていたのが…え、違う、聴いていただいていたのが…
what I was listening to just now... wait, no, what you were listening to...
もう完全に力が、え、無くなってしまいました。安心して。
I've completely, um, run out of strength, out of relief.
え、今聴いていただいたのが、なんと奏の初オリ曲！
What you just listened to was Kanade's very first original song!
『GREATEST』でーす！
“GREATEST”!
ふー！
Woohoo!
すごい！ジャケットが…
Look at that! The jacket cover...
え、作詞作曲はナナホシ管弦楽団…
Um, the lyricist and composer is Nanahoshi Orchestra...
かん、噛んじゃった、管弦楽団さんでーす！
Or- I stumbled over my words- Orchestra!
え、こちらの楽曲は、そうですね、どういう楽曲か、えーすごい…
Um, as for this track, well, to describe what kind of song it is...
言うと、がっ…こう、簡単に言うと！
To put it... simply, to put it simply!
え、韓国から夢を叶えに来た奏なりの、こう、
As Kanade, who came from Korea to fulfill her dream, it's like
ギラギラソング、キラキラソングみたいな感じとなって居まして、
a flashy, sparkling kind of song,
奏がこういうのを信じてやっていきたいんだ！みたいなのを伝えて、
and I conveyed how I want to keep going believing in this,
え、書いていただきました！
and they wrote it for me!
すごい、なんて素敵な歌詞を…
It's amazing, such wonderful lyrics...
本当に素敵な楽曲と歌詞をありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for such wonderful music and lyrics!
めっちゃ気に入ってます！
I love it so much!
そして！4月21日0時から、
And! Starting April 21st at midnight,
え、この後おそらく3時…あ、違う、3時間後に、
um, after this, probably at 3- wait, no, in 3 hours,
楽曲リリースもされます！
the song will also be released!
イェーイ！パチパチ！ありがとうー！
Yay! Clap clap! Thank you~!
すごい、最高すぎたわ。ありがとう。
It's amazing, that was so great. Thank you.
MVはね、ちょっと後日公開なんですけれども、
The MV will be released at a later date, though,
ぜひ公開されたらいっぱい見てくださーい！
please watch it a lot once it's out!
はい、新曲の披露もできたところで！
All right, now that I've unveiled my new song,
告知タイムです！
it's announcement time!
まず一つ目は、皆さんお待ちかね、
First up is what you've all been waiting for:
グッズの紹介でーす！
the merchandise lineup!
こちら！
Right here!
音乃瀬奏 誕生日記念2025、
Kanade Otonose Birthday Celebration 2025:
フルセットはこんな感じになってます！可愛いーーー！
Here is the full set! So cute!
可愛いやろ？可愛いやろ？ちょっとコメントにラグがあって拾いづらいんだが、
Cute, right? Cute, right? There's a bit of lag with comments so it's hard to read them, but...
「うおーおめでとう」「最高だったよ」「オリ曲！」
“Whoa, congrats!”, “It was amazing!”, “Original song!”
まだオリ曲のくだりかー！
You're still on the original song topic?!
え、今回のキービジュアルはごんじママに描いていただきましたー！
Um, this key visual was illustrated by Gonji-mama!
可愛いでしょー！
Isn't it adorable?!
まぁでもオリ曲だね！みんなすごい
Still, an original song! You guys are all so—
「念願のオリ曲！」みたいな感じだったから
like, "Finally, an original song!" so...
いっぱい喜んでもらえて嬉しいです！
I'm so glad everyone is so happy about it!
それではグッズ1つずつ見ていきましょう！
Now then, let's take a look at the merch one by one!
1つ目！
First item!
ワイドラバーマットー！
Wide rubber desk mat!
キービジュアルのオリジナルパジャマ着た奏の、きゃー！デザインのラバーマットです！
It's a rubber mat featuring Kanade in original pajamas from the key visual with a "kyaa!" design!
キーボードとマウスを乗せて使える、ワイドサイズになっています！
It's an extra-wide size that fits both your keyboard and mouse!
2つ目はこちら！
Here is the second item!
奏が落書きしちゃったTシャツです！
It's the "T-shirt Kanade doodled on"!
あの、実際に奏がね、描き下ろしデザインのTシャツです！
It's a T-shirt with a design freshly drawn by Kanade herself!
描きましたー！
I drew it!
よかったら奏と一緒に、Tシャツ1枚持ってる民になってくれませんか？
If you'd like, won't you join Kanade in becoming one of the "people who own one T-shirt"?
いっぱい買ってください！
Please buy lots of them!
続いて3つ目！
Next up, the third item!
タンブラーです！
A tumbler!
衣装のね、こちらの面をモチーフにした日常使いができる落ち着いたデザイン！
Featuring the ribbon from my outfit as a motif, it's a subtle design suitable for daily use!
会社などで使って、ぜひとも奏を宣伝してください！
Please use it at work or elsewhere, and spread the word about Kanade!
そして次はこちら！
And next is this!
奏のぷにぷにクッション！
Kanade's squishy cushion!
まあいっか！寝ている表情のフェイスクッションです！
Oh well! It's a face cushion with a sleeping expression!
特別に奏のほっぺをぷにぷにしてよしと台本に書かれていますが、
The script says, "You may squish Kanade's cheeks as a special treat,"
許可した覚えはありません！
but I have no memory of approving that!
ぷにぷにじゃないからな！
They aren't squishy, okay?!
はい！
Alright!
そして、フルセット購入特典はこちら！
And here is the full-set purchase bonus!
なんと奏、直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード！
A postcard with Kanade's handwritten signature and foil-stamped printed message!
今回数量限定ではないので、フルセットを買ってくれた方全員に直筆サインが届きます！
It's not limited quantity this time, so everyone who buys the full set will receive a handwritten signature!
みんな安心してね！戦争じゃないからゆっくり買ってもいいんだぞ！
Rest assured, everyone! It's not a war, so you can take your time buying!
奏腱鞘炎になりながら書くからね！
Kanade will write them all even if she gets tendonitis!
うわぁ、頑張って書くぞ！
Whoa, I'll do my best writing them!
今回は、誕生日記念2025お礼ボイスも付きまーす！
This time, it also comes with a Birthday Celebration 2025 Thank-You Voice!
さらに、フルセット特典として昨年の9月から発売された、ホロライブ公式カードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚付きます！
Furthermore, as a full-set bonus, you get one card usable in the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME on sale since last September!
カードはホロライブプロダクション公式ショップで購入された方のみ対象となります。
Note that the card is only for those who purchase from the hololive production official shop.
うわー！可愛い！
Whoa, so cute!
特典につくのは推しアピールできるキーカード、推しホロメンカードです！
The bonus is an "Oshi Holomen Card," a key card to show off your favorite talent!
カードの詳細や遊び方についてはホームページにてご確認ください！
Please check the official website for card details and how to play!
カードは日本語版のみとなりますのでご了承ください！
Please note that the card is only available in Japanese!
以上、グッズ紹介でした！
That concludes the merch showcase!
そして告知2つ目はこちら！
And here is the second announcement!
なんと！LINEスタンプ制作決定！すごーい！
LINE stickers are officially in production! Awesome!
可愛いでしょ？「すまそー」って。「すまそー」って言ってる。パチパチありがとー！
Isn't it cute? Saying "Suma-so" (sorry). She's saying "Suma-so." Thanks for the clapping!
えっと...
Um...
発売日はまだ未定ですが、こんな感じの可愛いイラストのスタンプです！イェーイ！
The release date is still undecided, but they're cute illustrated stickers like this! Yay!
セリフとかもね、奏が考えて作ってもらっているので乞うご期待！
Kanade came up with the lines and everything, so please look forward to them!
詳細は後日また告知をします！お楽しみに！
Details will be announced at a later date! Stay tuned!
以上、告知でしたー！
That's all for the announcements!
ということで！
And with that!
音乃瀬奏生誕祭2025、あ、違う、こっちだ！
Otonose Kanade Birthday Festival 2025—ah wait, this way!
毎回間違える、2025！
I always get it wrong—2025!
はい、いかがでしたでしょうかー？
Well, how did you all enjoy it?
初めてのね、アコギの挑戦だったり、
Between my first attempt at acoustic guitar,
ね、「すごいかっこいい！」ってコメントしてくれたの見たよー！
and seeing comments saying "So cool!", I saw them!
嬉しかったし、すごい頑張って準備したので、
It made me so happy, and I worked really hard preparing,
あの、いっぱい見ていただけて嬉しい限りです！
so I'm beyond thrilled that so many of you watched!
本当に嬉しいよ！オリ曲も公開できて！
I'm really so happy! Getting to reveal my original song too!
あの、リリースされたらいっぱい聴いてね！
Please listen to it a lot once it's released!
すごい、まだコメント欄がぷにぷにのくだりになってる(笑)
Wow, the comments are still stuck on the "squishy" part, haha.
遅ぇんだよ！予測して打て！拾えねぇだろ！
You're too slow! Predict it and type! How am I supposed to read it in time?!
えー、ということで、
Um, so anyway,
えー、この後のスケジュールをちょっとざっくり皆さんに教えしますと、
to give you all a quick overview of the schedule after this,
21時10分からグッズ販売開始を行います！
merch sales will begin at 21:10!
そして、21時20分から、あ、こっちだ、
And from 21:20—ah, this way—
20分からメンバーシップ限定の
from 21:20, we have the membership-only
アンコールライブもありますので、そちらもよろしくお願いします！
encore stream, so please look forward to that too!
今がメン限買い時だよ、みんな！
Now's the best time to join the membership, everyone!
今、今今！今入んな！はい！
Now, right now! Join now! Alright!
そして、多分もう終わりかな？忘れてないよね？
And... that should be everything? I haven't forgotten anything, right?
はい、ということで、では！おつ奏でしたー！
Okay, with that, thanks for watching—otsu-Kanade!
来てくれてありがとうー！イェーイ！
Thank you so much for coming! Yay!
あ、待って待って待って！待って待って待って！待って待って！
Ah, wait wait wait! Wait wait wait! Wait wait!
1個、大事なの忘れてた！
I forgot one important thing!
一番大事なお知らせ！はい、告知！
The most important announcement! Yes, announcement!
それでは、みなさん聴いてください。奏からの、
Now then, everyone please listen. From Kanade,
もう、オリ曲並みに大事なお知らせ！
an announcement just as important as an original song!
デデン！あしたは月曜日！
Ta-da! Tomorrow is Monday!
月曜日...月曜日...るるるるる...
Monday... Monday... Lurururu...
みんな夢から覚める時間だよー。もう夢から覚める時間だよー。
It's time for everyone to wake up from the dream. Time to wake up from the dream now.
奏の生誕ライブは、アンコールライブが終わったらもう終わりなんだよー。えーん。
Once the encore live ends, Kanade's birthday live is all over. Waaah.
明日は学校だね、会社だね。えーん。
Tomorrow is school, or work. Waaah.
見てくれてありがとうー！やっと夢に向けた一歩踏み出せました！私はもっともっと輝きたい！
[Text] Thank you for watching! I've finally taken a step toward my dream! I want to shine even brighter!
夢に描いた夢を全部叶えたい！もっと素敵な景色を見せられるようにがんばります！押忍！ 音乃瀬奏
[Text] I want to make all the dreams I pictured come true! I'll work hard to show you even greater sights! Osu! - Otonose Kanade
Error processing subtitles for this segment.